si.edu 2019-11-15

# North American Privacy Policy | Blackbaud

At Blackbaud, we are committed to protecting your privacy. You can travel through most of our site without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request. This Website Privacy Policy (“Policy”) provides you with information concerning our practices and procedures as they relate specifically to information we collect at this website. If you have additional questions or would like further information on this topic, please feel free to write to us at [webmaster@blackbaud.com](mailto:webmaster@blackbaud.com). By visiting this website, you are accepting the practices described herein. We may update this Policy from time to time, so please check this Policy periodically for changes.

### Collecting your Personal Information

We do not collect any personal information about you at our website unless you choose to provide it to us voluntarily. We define “personal information” as information that personally identifies you or allows us to contact you. Such information might include your phone number, name or email address. Generally, this information is requested when you are asked to register before entering a contest, subscribing to e-mail newsletters, completing an online survey, joining a limited-access premium site, viewing premium-level resource information, or when requesting information about or purchasing Blackbaud products and services. If you encounter a screen or page that requests information you do not want to share with us, do not enter the information and do not proceed with that screen or page.

You can personalize your experience at [www.blackbaud.com](https://www.blackbaud.com/) by becoming a registered user. If you ever want to review or update your profile, simply visit [www.blackbaud.com](https://www.blackbaud.com/) and edit your account information. We’ll ask you to disclose your User ID and password so that only you can access your profile. Your account information is secure and is accessible by using a password that you select. Do not share your password with anyone. The Blackbaud website assigns a personal identification number and sends it to your computer in the form of a small text file, called a “cookie.” The use of this cookie allows you to visit other password-restricted portions of Blackbaud’s website—for which you have security access—without having to sign in again.

### Use of your Personal Information

If you do provide us with personal information, we will only use it for the purposes described where it is collected or elsewhere on the website. Specifically, we may use your personal information in the following ways: (1) to make the website easier for you to use by not making you enter your personal information more than once; (2) to help you quickly find information on Blackbaud software, services and customer support; (3) to help us create and deliver content most relevant to you; and (4) to alert you to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new services from Blackbaud.

We will not sell, license, transmit or disclose your personal information outside of Blackbaud or its affiliates without notice to you unless (1) you expressly authorize us to do so, (2) it is necessary to allow our service providers, representatives, or agents to provide services for or to us, (3) it is necessary to provide our products or services to you, (4) it is disclosed to entities that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other entities with whom we have joint marketing or other agreements, (5) it is necessary or we deem it appropriate in connection with a sale of all or substantially all of the assets or business of Blackbaud, a sale of stock or equity interests of Blackbaud, or the merger of Blackbaud into another entity or any consolidation, share exchange, combination, reorganization, or like transaction in which Blackbaud is not the survivor, (6) it is necessary to protect and defend the rights or property of Blackbaud, (7) it is necessary to act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Blackbaud customers, visitors to Blackbaud’s website or the public, or (8) otherwise as we are required or permitted by law.

We occasionally contract with other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering purchases, answering customer questions about products or services, sending postal mail and processing event registration. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

If you are a California resident, you may ask us to disclose certain information about or to refrain from sharing your information (whether collected online or offline) with third parties for their marketing purposes. Please tell us your preference by contacting us as indicated in the “Contacting Us” section of this Policy.

### Information Collected from Children

[www.Blackbaud.com](https://www.blackbaud.com/) is a general audience site, and we do not knowingly collect information about children or sell products to children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you must ask your parent or guardian to assist you in using our website. Furthermore, we may restrict entries to any contests, sweepstakes or promotions to entrants who are at least 18 years of age.

### Marketing Communications

We may contact you about promotions, customer stories, Blackbaud news and updates, or thought leadership content. We may send these communications via email or postal mail, call your organization, or serve you advertisements on our website. If you would no longer like to receive such emails, please follow the “Unsubscribe” instructions at the end of each email. Your e-mail address will be removed from our marketing list. Please allow us a reasonable period of time in order to satisfy your request, as some promotions may already be in process. To opt out of being contacted by any other communication methods, please contact us at [webmaster@blackbaud.com](mailto:webmaster@blackbaud.com).

### Email

We appreciate your questions and comments about our website and services and welcome your email messages to mailboxes listed on our website. We will share your messages with those within and outside our organization who may be able to address the issues contained in your message. We will keep a copy of your message until we have had an opportunity to address your concerns. We may archive your message for a certain period of time or discard it, but your email message will not be used for any other purpose.

### Access to your Personal Information

We will provide you with the means to ensure that your personal information is correct and current. If you are a registered user of our website, you may review and update this information at any time on [www.blackbaud.com](https://www.blackbaud.com/). Registered users can view and edit personal information they have already given us. All users can subscribe or unsubscribe to Blackbaud email newsletters and blogs.

We require you to enter your password for security purposes before you update your email address, user name, password, and/or your security question and answer. If you change your email address, we send an email to both your old and new email addresses.

### Security of your Personal Information

We restrict access to personal information collected about you at our website to our employees, our affiliates’ employees, those who are otherwise specified in this Policy, or others who need to know that information to provide services to you or in the course of conducting our business operations or activities. While no website can guarantee security, we maintain appropriate physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information collected via the website. We protect our databases with various physical, technical and procedural measures and we restrict access to your information by unauthorized persons. We also advise all Blackbaud employees about their responsibility to protect customer data and we provide them with appropriate guidelines for adhering to our company’s business ethics standards and confidentiality policies. Inside Blackbaud, data is stored in password-controlled servers with limited access.

### Links to Other Websites

For your convenience, we may provide links to other websites and web pages that we do not control. We cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of any websites or pages not under our control and we do not endorse any of these websites or pages, the services or products described or offered on such sites or pages, or any of the content contained on those sites or pages.

### Use of Cookies

A cookie is a piece of information that a web server may place on your computer when you visit a website. Cookies are commonly used by websites to improve the user experience and have not been known to transmit computer viruses or otherwise harm your computer. Many cookies last only through a single website session, or visit. Others may have an expiration date, or may remain on your computer until you delete them.

We may use cookies for a number of purposes—for example, to maintain continuity during a user session, to gather data about the usage of our website for research and other purposes, to store your preferences for certain kinds of information and marketing offers, or to store a user name or encrypted identification number so that you do not have to provide this information every time you return to our website. To ensure we are publishing content customers need and want, Blackbaud collects aggregated site-visitation statistics using cookies. When someone visits the site, a cookie is placed on the customer’s machine (if the customer accepts cookies) or is read if the customer has visited the website previously. 

Our cookies will track only your activity relating to your online activity on this website, and will not track your other Internet activity. Our cookies do not gather personally identifiable information.

You can decide if and how your computer will accept a cookie by configuring your preferences or options in your browser. However, if you choose to reject cookies, you may not be able to use certain of our online products and services or website features. For example, if you choose to not have your browser accept cookies from Blackbaud’s website, you will need to re-enter your personal information each time that you attempt to access premium information.

Certain pages on our websites contain “web beacons” (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). These web beacons allow third parties to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies set by the third party.

An IP address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit our website, we may view the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. We use this information to determine the general physical location of the device and understand from what regions of the world our website visitors come. We also may use this information to enhance our website.

We do not currently take actions to respond to Do Not Track signals sent by your Internet browser because a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed. In the future, we may adopt a standard once appropriate new technologies are created and will make any corresponding changes to this Policy.

### Contests, Sweepstakes and Other Promotions

On our website, you may wish to participate in contests, sweepstakes and other promotions that we may offer from time to time. Through these promotions, you may choose to participate in activities such as sharing information found on our websites with others and sending email invitations. If you choose to participate in these promotions, and are eligible to do so, we may ask you for information such as your name, email address, date of birth and telephone number.

In connection with any contests, sweepstakes and other promotions that we may offer from time to time via the website, we use the information you provide to administer the contests, sweepstakes and other promotions. We also may use the information to communicate with you, or the other people you select, about our products and services or our partners may use such information to communicate with you about the contests, sweepstakes or other promotions or their products and services. As mentioned above, if you create a profile and submit an entry in connection with a contest or promotion, your name, profile and entry, but not your email address, phone number and age, will be visible to other website users. We will not use information you provide about other people for any purpose except the purpose you direct without first getting their consent.

### Transfer of Information

Blackbaud is headquartered in the United States of America. Any personal information you provide may be stored and maintained in a secure database in the United States. If you are a resident of a country other than the United States and provide us with your information, you consent to the transfer of your data into the United States.

### Changes to this Policy

Blackbaud may update this Policy at any time and from time to time and we will post any changes to this page. The most recent version of the Policy is reflected by the version date located at the bottom of this Policy.

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Policy or would like to learn more about how we protect privacy, please write to us at Blackbaud, Inc., 2000 Daniel Island Drive, Charleston, SC, 29492-7541, USA or at [webmaster@blackbaud.com](mailto:webmaster@blackbaud.com).

Last updated September 18, 2019

## Blackbaud Privacy Shield Notice

### Privacy Shield

This is a United States-based website and is subject to United States law. Laws related to Personal Data vary by country. For example, Personal Data collected in the European Union is subject to laws based on the European Union Data Protection Directive. Blackbaud, its subsidiaries, and its affiliates are certified under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework regarding the collection, storage, transfer, use and other processing of Personal Data transferred from the European Union, the United Kingdom, and Switzerland, as applicable, to the United States.

[Click here](https://www.blackbaud.com/privacy-shield) to view our Privacy Shield Notice
